<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joe Canero</title>
    <description>Joe Canero&#39;s developer site. Check out his blog and his code samples.
</description>
    <link>caneroj1.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="caneroj1.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 10:01:06 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 10:01:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Awesome Beer Fridge</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  The &quot;Beer Fridge of Awesomeness&quot; is a cool project I found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/InitialState/beerfridge&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;
  that walks you through using a Raspberry Pi to build your very own smart beer fridge!
  The Beer Fridge can detect when it&#39;s open, measure its temperature and count the number of bottles inside.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog-header&quot;&gt;First Things First&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I&#39;ve never used a Raspberry Pi before, so first I had to get my Ultimate Starter Kit. The project has a pretty long list of required parts, so I had to order those as well.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Amongst other things, I ordered a digital thermometer and some door sensors, and the total cost for everything was around $120.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#39;blog-post-pic&#39; src=&#39;/images/6272015setup.jpg&#39;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog-header&quot;&gt;The Pi is Almost Done&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Installing Raspbian, the default Raspberry Pi OS was pretty simple. There&#39;s a tool called
      NOOBS, that pretty much does it for you.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I was pretty much playing the waiting game at this point.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#39;blog-post-pic&#39; src=&#39;/images/6272015rbpi.jpg&#39;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog-header&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
      The Raspberry Pi needed some way to count the number of bottles in the fridge, so I had to
      connect the Raspberry Pi, via bluetooth, to a Wii Fit Balance Board and place the fridge on top.
      Then I was able to measure the weight of the       fridge.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;center-align&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#39;blog-post-pic&#39; src=&#39;/images/6272015wii.jpg&#39; style=&#39;width: 60%;&#39;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
      The next step was to start wiring everything up.
      Some of the parts necessary for the beer fridge to be totally awesome include a temperature sensor
      and a door sensor. Getting these working with the Raspberry Pi was the most difficult part of the project,
      and required a steady hand. Below is the fully wired Pi.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;center-align&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#39;blog-post-pic&#39; src=&#39;/images/6272015fridge.jpg&#39; style=&#39;width: 60%;&#39;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog-header&quot;&gt;Finishing Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#39;col m6 s12&#39;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      All the sensors were working at this point, so it was time to fill the fridge! As I mentioned before, you should fill
      the fridge with beverages that all weigh pretty much the same. After loading up on Summer Shandy, I weighed the fridge with
      the bottles inside in order to determine each bottle&#39;s weight.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#39;col m6 s12&#39;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#39;blog-post-pic&#39; src=&#39;/images/6272015beer.jpg&#39; style=&#39;width: 80%;&#39;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog-header&quot;&gt;Project Complete!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
      Finally, the tutorial sets you up on a neat visualization dashboard where you can see the status of your beer fridge and monitor
      things like temperature and the number of bottles inside.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;center-align&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#39;blog-post-pic&#39; src=&#39;/images/6272015final.png&#39; style=&#39;width:80%;&#39;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog-header&quot;&gt;Closing Remarks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
      In the end, I thought the Beer Fridge of Awesomeness was a nice project to help me kill some time. It was my first exposure
      to working with a Raspberry Pi, and I learned a fair amount about setting up circuits and other hardware. I&#39;m on the lookout for my next
      project!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>caneroj1.github.io/raspberrypi/node/js/2015/06/27/awesome-beer-fridge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">caneroj1.github.io/raspberrypi/node/js/2015/06/27/awesome-beer-fridge.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>raspberrypi</category>
        
        <category>node</category>
        
        <category>js</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
